CHRIS CAMPBELL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+1 248 877 0395

Denver, CO LinkedIn

Portfolio

christopherecampbell@gmail.com

GitHub

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer with experience creating beautiful and useful applications with React, JavaScript, and TypeScript. I can create RESTful APIs for SQL and NoSQL databases and incorporate open APIs into backend applications. My previous experience includes managing revenue generating teams of up to 50; 9 years experience working in the e-commerce space for venture-backed companies ranging from seed stage to pre-IPO; and 3 years entrepreneurial experience as an award winning realtor. I'm looking to leverage my technical, interpersonal, and leadership skills to bring value to your team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- CSS

- JavaScript
 React.js
 Express.js
 Node.js RESTful Routing
- MongoDBPostgreSQLJSON

 - APIs

- Git
- GitHub
- Google Oauth
- JWT

INTERPERSONAL AND BUSINESS SKILLS

- Leadership
- Team BuildingTeam BuildingOKRs
- Strategic Planning

- Change Management
- Problem Solving
- Collaboration

PROJECTS

Après

GitHub | App | Video

I used React.js and TypeScript to create a marketplace where users can buy and sell used ski and snowboarding gear. The marketplace connects to an API built with Express.js and PostgreSQL for full CRUD functionality for listings.

- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify and prioritize features and requirements
- Conduct code reviews and provide feedback to improve code quality
- Develop and execute unit tests and perform system testing to ensure software quality
- Troubleshoot and resolve software defects and issues

Butter

GitHub | App | Video

Butter is a node.js cookbook application that lets you search, save, import, and copy recipes that you can edit and leave notes on over time. No more guessing on if you used 2 or 3 tablespoons of turmeric in that curry you love!

- Connected to Edamam's recipe search API, used API response to render recipes and link to original recipe source.
- Built a web scraper to allow users to easily import recipe data including images by just entering the url of the recipe.
- Deployed full CRUD functionality for multiple data resources stored in MongoDB with Express.js backend.
- Implemented authentication and authorization via Google OAuth preventing users from altering data they don't own.

FreshStart

GitHub | App | Video

In one week, my team coordinated across 3 time zones to create a mobile-first social media platform connecting wellness creators with people starting a wellness journey and an API with full CRUD for multiple data resources.

- Built reusable React, is components for consistent design throughout the app and a mobile first flexbox design.
- Implemented JSON Web Token authorization and authentication to protect users' data on the app from being edited.
- Connected to Cloudinary's API to allow users to take photos with their mobile devices and upload them to the app.
- Ensured our team was on track to meet our deliverables with minimal merge conflicts as our team's Scrum Manager.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dream Home Denver, LLC

Owner • Jun 2020-Nov 2022 • Denver, CO

- Built two websites with WordPress to market my real estate business and generate leads for target neighborhoods
- Provided innovative solutions leading to over \$10MM in closed sales volume to date across 25 transactions
- Broke records for price per square foot on listings at 550 E 12th Ave and 100 Park Ave West
- Designed a cohesive brand identity used across all marketing channels including print, social media, and events
- Awarded the International Sterling Society award by Coldwell Banker Realty for production in 2022
- Recognized as part of the "Best of Zillow" in the Denver Market

1stdibs (Nasdaq: DIBS)

Senior Director of Sales • Jul 2019-Apr 2020 • Denver, CO

- Opened a satellite office in Denver in two months that saved 1stdibs 20% per full time employee total cost
- Hired both individual contributors and managers to build a team of 30 across NYC, Denver, and London offices
- Represented the voice of the customer to achieve go to market fit for 1stdibs Trade offering
- Consistently had some of the highest employee engagement scores both for overall job satisfaction and satisfaction with management in the entire company

1stdibs (Nasdaq: DIBS)

Director of Sales • May 2019-Jul 2019 • New York, NY

- Grew 1stdibs Trade annual gross merchandise value from \$50MM to \$100MM between 2017 and 2019 by increasing total number of active clients and average spend per client
- Worked cross functionally with marketing, product, and other customer facing teams to launch industry leading trade rewards program
- Introduced consultative sales and wrote documentation for sales process along with training and onboarding
- Created a brand new sales function complete with comp plans and sales process to address a declining number of new customers across our trade and consumer businesses
- Doubled the response rate of emails through sales automation and A/B testing of email strategy
- Partnered with the People Team to create a predictable hiring process and best practices resulting in fast, quality hiring that was adapted
 to other departments across the company
- Developed 5 reps into highly effective managers across sales, customer experience and sales operations
- Decreased time spent on non-sales activities by 47%

Homepolish

Director of Commercial Sales • Jun 2016-Mar 2017 • New York, NY

- Implemented Salesforce.com from scratch including vetting implementation partners, creating custom objects, workflows, and dashboards to increase overall visibility into our business and empower revenue generating employees across business units
- Doubled the average gross profit per commercial customer
- Built sales team and process from the ground up with a 65% close rate on identified opportunities
- Developed the company's first ever system for compensation plans and commission structures for Sales Development Rep and Account Executive roles
- Led forecasting and goal setting for 2017 across all business units by analyzing historical sales data for the company to uncover insights

LANGUAGES

- Native English speaker
- Fluent in Spanish
- Conversational Italian

EDUCATION

BS in Communication - Cum Laude

University of Miami • 2009 Majors: Media Management and Spanish Minor: Business Administration

Certificate in Full Stack Software Engineering

General Assembly • 2003

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies